<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roadtrip on Jill Munson</title>
    <link>http://jillmunson.com/tags/roadtrip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roadtrip on Jill Munson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:51:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jillmunson.com/tags/roadtrip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadtrip Day [0] - Columbus, OH</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/11-2/day-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:51:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/11-2/day-0/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For the next 7 days, Ryan and I are making our own version of the Oregon trail (from New York to Seattle), along with the dog and everything we own in one of these&lt;img src=&#34;http://jillmunson.com/img/covered_wagon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;All of the fording the river jokes have been made&#34; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peak levels of &amp;lsquo;Murica have been reached, folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a history of making excuses based on overplayed stereotypes of salt-of-the-earth folk and cultural incest in an effort to avoid the awkward conversation about my policy of never moving to anywhere where I might be the most &amp;ldquo;ethnic&amp;rdquo; looking person in the zip code.  It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to write off entire swaths of the country this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, in an effort to enjoy the 48+ hours of driving and weeklong stay in the heart of the nation I&amp;rsquo;m going to put aside my cultural identity crisis for the time being and learn as much as I can about each of the cities and towns that we are staying in along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;day-0-columbus-oh:36c8cb37135652849af48a5409799526&#34;&gt;Day 0 - Columbus, OH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to this trip, all I knew about Ohio was that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My dad briefly went to college there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They have two football teams&lt;br /&gt;
and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People there love this spaghetti dish called &lt;a href=&#34;http://jillmunson.com/img/skyline.jpg&#34;&gt;Skyline Chili&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a ton of time to do research.  We got to the hotel at 4am, across the street from the county court so not exactly a picturesque historic downtown sort of area.&lt;br /&gt;
On the entrance of the hotel we were staying at, I noticed a plaque next to the entrance that said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;National Register of Historic Places: The Great Southern Hotel&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Historic Register documentation &lt;a href=&#34;http://focus.nps.gov/AssetDetail/NRIS/82001458&#34;&gt;has not been digitized at this time&lt;/a&gt; but from what I could gather from my limited resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hotel opened in 1896 or 1897 (the hotel&amp;rsquo;s website and wikipedia differ on this).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior to its opening, a series of fires destroyed some of the most prominent hotels in Columbus.  The Great Southern Hotel &amp;amp; Theater was an undertaking to replace the city gathering spaces and cultural centers that were lost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The building was designed to be &amp;ldquo;fireproof&amp;rdquo;, was also one of the first in the city to both use and produce electricity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theater was reopened in 1998, after a $10MM renovation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish we had gotten to stay a bit longer and explore the hotel and the surrounding city.  Meryl and I took an early morning walk in the surrounding area, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t find too much besides the &lt;a href=&#34;http://columbuscommons.org/&#34;&gt;Columbus Commons&lt;/a&gt; and some under construction high-rise apartments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like we missed out on Ohio having only spent about 5-6 hours in Columbus and not in a very exciting neighborhood at that, so any suggestions on places to see or things to do the next time we hit the state would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>