<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jill Munson</title>
    <link>http://jillmunson.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jill Munson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 10:54:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jillmunson.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Homecoming</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2019/12-30/homecoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2019/12-30/homecoming/</guid>
      <description>We need a reboot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Model and The View</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/8-3/model-and-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 17:11:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/8-3/model-and-view/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Are you sure you did that work? I remember things differently.&amp;rdquo;
I&#39;ve never been more sure of anything in my life.
Over the course of a lifetime, I have developed an incredibly well-defined sense of self. In a world of imposter syndrome seminars and #askformore campaigns, it can feel like this identity that I have declared my own is in some way rooted in false bravado. I prefer to think of it as the result of having lived a life running in the debugger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SOHCAHTOA: A CSS War Story</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2017/7-9/using-sohcahtoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 09:17:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2017/7-9/using-sohcahtoa/</guid>
      <description>Dmitri PopovI decided to split this into parts, because I had a great time at I/O and there was a lot to learn and experience over 3 days.
(Additional disclaimer: I do not present myself as a representative of Amazon nor does anything I say here confirm, deny or relate to any business strategy, priorities or initiatives currently being undertaken at Amazon. Any mention of Amazon products are presented as my personal opinion as a technology consumer, not as an employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIRR On-Time Performance</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/twitter/otp-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 13:22:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/twitter/otp-bot/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadtrip Day [0] - Columbus, OH</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/11-2/day-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:51:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/11-2/day-0/</guid>
      <description>For the next 7 days, Ryan and I are making our own version of the Oregon trail (from New York to Seattle), along with the dog and everything we own in one of these.
Peak levels of &amp;lsquo;Murica have been reached, folks.
 I have a history of making excuses based on overplayed stereotypes of salt-of-the-earth folk and cultural incest in an effort to avoid the awkward conversation about my policy of never moving to anywhere where I might be the most &amp;ldquo;ethnic&amp;rdquo; looking person in the zip code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/meetups/nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 11:27:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/meetups/nyc/</guid>
      <description>1. DigitalOcean Meetup Community Organizer: Digital Ocean
Why?: Besides swag, pizza, and beer, they are super involved in the open source devops community and contribute to core docker libraries. They tend to get really great speakers, the organizer for the NY office is a woman and they host women in tech events and provide venue space for other meetups on this list.
2. Women Who Code NYC Organizer: Women Who Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Day at Viacom</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/10-29/goodbye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 17:11:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/10-29/goodbye/</guid>
      <description>At the time of writing, this moment is:
  my last day with Nick digital,
  3 days before I start a cross-country adventure with my micro-family on our way to put down new roots and start the Seattle chapter of our lives,
  2 hours before my going away party starts,
  about 20 minutes before the Minibar delivery gets here.
   I started to wind down the day by writing one of those horrible &amp;ldquo;last day for ______&amp;rdquo; emails that read less like a parting note and more like a final treatise on so-and-so&#39;s insights that will motivate and steer the company towards greatness while complimenting a large number of people that person has probably never met.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craft as meditation</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/8-3/craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 17:11:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/8-3/craft/</guid>
      <description>I get restless sometimes.
I work in the city, and thus have the distinct pleasure of a long train commute. I have lots of time on my hands to do a lot of thinking while sitting still.
I think about lots of things &amp;ndash; work, side projects, what am I doing with my life, etc. but if I&#39;m not doing something with my hands I get perpetually distracted from my own thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiku.py</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/haiku/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 14:47:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/haiku/about/</guid>
      <description>Link: haiku.jillmunson.com
no longer hosted on google app engine, currently migrating to AWS so stay tuned :)
Github: haiku.py
A work in progress JSON API haiku-as-a-service. Built with Flask on top of the provided sample application from CP:100, deployed on google app engine
 v.01 - Counting syllables with nltk and CMU pronouncing dictionary This all started as a demo app for google app engine that I was tweaking as part of CP:100, an introduction to Google Cloud Platform that was organized by GDG-NYC (side note: they are awesome and run some really awesome meetups so if you are in the area, go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary tree reconstruction and the phylogeny of the domestic dog pt. 1: Phylogenetic trees and edit distance</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/7-11/phylogeny-and-dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 12:57:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/7-11/phylogeny-and-dogs/</guid>
      <description>I love life sciences, dogs, and algorithms so when I found this paper describing recent changes to the hypothesized phylogeny of modern dog I got giddy.
Dogs are incredibly fascinating, regardless of your opinion on breed standards and dog shows. They are the only successfully domesticated carnivore, they have the ability to understand our social communication mechanics and language, they engage in mutually beneficial social cooperation with us and we are not absolutely certain of why or when it happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello world</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/7-10/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 12:57:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/7-10/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m not sure when this all began, but right now it is July 10th and about halfway through what I consider real summer and I have been plagued by this near-constant sense that I should be doing something. It&#39;s not like I don&#39;t keep myself busy, but lately I feel like none of those things require any kind of boundary pushing.
The issue is that even though I like what I&#39;m doing, I don&#39;t feel like I&#39;ve done anything start-to-finish and like I&#39;m learning anything new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 22:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/about/</guid>
      <description>pictured above: Me with my husband Ryan, Thomas immortalized as lord of the dance at our wedding
English nerd -&amp;gt; Seawolf -&amp;gt; software engineer @ Viacom -&amp;gt; cross-country road warrior.
Currently on hiatus from code monkeying for a week before starting my new job as an SDE @ Amazon on the video advertising team.
Corg-mom to a cardigan welsh corgi named Meryl although this guy is much better at this whole rocking the &amp;ldquo;Corgi parent&amp;rdquo; thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jillmunson.com &#43; hugo</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/hugo/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 22:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/hugo/about/</guid>
      <description>Github: jaemu.github.io
 One of the biggest weaknesses I have is putting pen to paper, finger to keyboard, etc. without getting overwhelmed by trying to organize something that isn&#39;t even there. Even in writing, my comfort zone was always editing and not content creation (I blame this background for my preference for hunting bugs and re-organizing code than architecting an application from scratch). I think as you get more knowledge without constantly exercising that knowledge with repeated exercise this becomes incredibly common.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>