<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jill Munson</title>
    <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jill Munson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 12:57:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jillmunson.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>hello world</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/7-10/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 12:57:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/7-10/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure when this all began, but right now it is July 10th and about halfway through what I consider real summer and I have been plagued by this near-constant sense that I should be doing something.  It&amp;rsquo;s not like I don&amp;rsquo;t keep myself busy, but lately I feel like none of those things require any kind of boundary pushing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is that even though I like what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve done anything start-to-finish and like I&amp;rsquo;m learning anything new.  Sure I&amp;rsquo;m quickly becoming the world&amp;rsquo;s largest living encyclopedia of browser and javascript quirks but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been missing the sort of really stressful but incredibly satisfying high that comes from finally grok&amp;rsquo;ing lamdas or dynamic programming or the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, I miss school.  Not just my friends, I miss being in the trenches every day and having people who could completely empathize and working together not because we were on the same team but because it was a culture of stay competitive but help out the next person because strong competition made everyone better.  I am willing to admit I am romenticizing this a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I never got around to making any new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions, but 7 months later is better than never right?  So that&amp;rsquo;s what I did &amp;ndash; I made a list of knowledge resolutions that I want to say I know and have experience doing and doing &lt;em&gt;well&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a new website with a blog and a project section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete at least one small library/module/plugin/etc in javascript (&lt;a href=&#34;http://tholman.com/elevator.js/&#34;&gt;this is my inspiration&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udacity.com/nanodegree&#34;&gt;android nanodegree&lt;/a&gt; and build a tiny app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brush up on actually implementing algorithms (DFS, djikstra&amp;rsquo;s, suffix tree implementation, etc etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write about at least one technical problem or thing I learned once a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list is purposely impossible.  By putting down all of the things I want to do, I&amp;rsquo;m identifying all of the parts of my big messy brain house instead of getting overwhelmed by the volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>