<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jill Munson</title>
    <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jill Munson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 13:22:42 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jillmunson.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LIRR On-Time Performance</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/twitter/otp-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 13:22:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/twitter/otp-bot/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiku.py</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/haiku/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 14:47:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/haiku/about/</guid>
      <description>Link: haiku.jillmunson.com
no longer hosted on google app engine, currently migrating to AWS so stay tuned :)
Github: haiku.py
A work in progress JSON API haiku-as-a-service. Built with Flask on top of the provided sample application from CP:100, deployed on google app engine
 v.01 - Counting syllables with nltk and CMU pronouncing dictionary This all started as a demo app for google app engine that I was tweaking as part of CP:100, an introduction to Google Cloud Platform that was organized by GDG-NYC (side note: they are awesome and run some really awesome meetups so if you are in the area, go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jillmunson.com &#43; hugo</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/hugo/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 22:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/hugo/about/</guid>
      <description>Github: jaemu.github.io
 One of the biggest weaknesses I have is putting pen to paper, finger to keyboard, etc. without getting overwhelmed by trying to organize something that isn&#39;t even there. Even in writing, my comfort zone was always editing and not content creation (I blame this background for my preference for hunting bugs and re-organizing code than architecting an application from scratch). I think as you get more knowledge without constantly exercising that knowledge with repeated exercise this becomes incredibly common.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>