<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jill Munson</title>
    <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jill Munson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 14:47:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jillmunson.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiku.py</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/haiku/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 14:47:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/haiku/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jaemu/google-cloud-cp100&#34;&gt;google-cloud-cp100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://haiku.jillmunson.com/haiku/you&#34;&gt;haiku.jillmunson.com/haiku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://haiku.jillmunson.com/syllable/flower&#34;&gt;haiku.jillmunson.com/syllable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A work in progress JSON API haiku-as-a-service.  Built with Flask on top of the provided sample application from CP:100, deployed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/appengine/docs&#34;&gt;google app engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireworks.js</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/firework/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 22:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/firework/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A silly project that launches fireworks from click or touch events&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jillmunson.com &#43; hugo</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/hugo/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 22:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/hugo/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jaemu/jaemu.github.io&#34;&gt;jaemu.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest weaknesses I have is putting pen to paper, finger to keyboard, etc. without getting overwhelmed by trying to organize something that isn&amp;rsquo;t even there.  Even in writing, my comfort zone was always editing and not content creation (I blame this background for my preference for hunting bugs and re-organizing code than architecting an application from scratch).  I think as you get more knowledge without constantly exercising that knowledge with repeated exercise this becomes incredibly common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a primarily front-end developer, this overthinking paralysis has stricken me every time I&amp;rsquo;ve tried making a personal site.  I&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with different blog engines, tried rolling my own, even tried just hard-coding static html pages as a thought experiment to try and identify the different pain points that were causing me to throw in the towel every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I learned several things about myself and side projects in general:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lesson-0-you-might-not-need-javascript-insert-favorite-language-here:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Lesson 0 - You &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; not need (javascript|insert favorite language here)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started thinking about what I needed, I started looking into &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tryghost/Ghost&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, which is a full blog engine with a ton of features out of the box, 3rd-party plugins, etc.  Ghost is great and from my little time with it, seems like the kind of thing that could really fit the use case of needing a blog engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I started getting set up with it though, I realized that for what I wanted (a personal site to host blog posts, images, and project pages) I didn&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a full-fledged backend and thus didn&amp;rsquo;t really need a server to serve content.  What I really wanted was something that generated static content and could be served from something like AWS S3 or Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an important realization for me because one of my major problems was just identifying what it was that I wanted to build.  Even though I could run a self-hosted instance of Ghost, that required a lot of additional configuration and setup that while not &lt;em&gt;difficult&lt;/em&gt; per se was an additional headache (not even going into my gun-shyness with securing a public web server after a fiasco with an EC2 instance that I was running for a network security project of all things).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I was completely comfortable with nodejs and have been working on an incredibly dyanmic single-page application entirely in javascript, the things that nick.com need to do vs. what I wanted my site to do were wildly different in scope and complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned not to overcomplicate things just for the sake of &amp;ldquo;learning&amp;rdquo; and to make the right thing for the right task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lesson-1-while-not-always-the-right-way-to-go-doing-something-the-hard-way-first-teaches-you-a-lot-about-what-you-re-trying-to-build:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Lesson 1: While not always the right way to go, doing something the hard way first teaches you a lot about what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to build&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say that I learned my lesson and continued on without making things overly complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I thought &amp;ldquo;well I can write my &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; static site generator for nodejs!  With recursion and partials and more!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an experiment to figure out what features I would need to do so, I tried hand-rolling my own site.  In hindsight, this is like milking a cow to figure out how to make an ice cream machine but hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very least, I identified some pain points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-usable HTML templates and partials are not just a nice to have, they are a necessity.  Otherwise, woe is the developer trying to keep an ever-growing number of static files consistently pointing to the right file references, using the same class names for elements across pages, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing a static HTML generator is foolhardy for several reasons, least of which is the existence of Markdown compilers.  I realized one of the biggest advantages of using Markdown is that not only is there a common language that compiles to the same elements, but it gives you the freedom to use inline HTML when absolutely necessary.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing responsive CSS from scratch is a pain.  I don&amp;rsquo;t care how long you have been doing front-end development, writing clean, maintainable, working CSS without Less/Stylus/Sass and a framework is an exercise in frustration.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were probably many more, but that was about as far as I got before having a conversation with my friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.robxu9.com/&#34;&gt;Rob&lt;/a&gt; about what I was trying to do.  He suggested &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lesson-2-done-is-better-than-perfect-or-why-you-shouldn-t-give-up-on-something-the-first-time-it-doesn-t-work-the-way-you-expect-it-to:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Lesson 2: Done is better than perfect, or why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t give up on something the first time it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work the way you expect it to.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started with hugo was extremely easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what to do from there was not as easy.  Hugo expects to create a new folder within the current directory of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site (sitename)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and if that folder already exists, throws an error.  If it were me, I would have created a new site within that folder or at least created an option to pass a flag that indicates that this is what I want to do, especially when migrating content from an existing github repo that has the strict requirement of having the name (github_name).github.io.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got past that, I stumbled on the configuration bit.  Hugo expects a config.(toml|yaml|json) file, but not all of the params are documented.  This becomes a problem when trying to add data to partials because &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; data is global in scope but others like custom params are under the .Site.Params namespace.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/configuration/&#34;&gt;This is all that I was able to find&lt;/a&gt;, and while most of the params are documented some are given no explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also some reduntant functionality.  In the config file, you can specify which theme you want to use but you can also compile your project with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo -t (theme_name)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which is fine, but again not super well documented as to why you would want to use one and not the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point is, it&amp;rsquo;s ok to struggle with a tool out of the box.  The beauty of open source is that if something doesn&amp;rsquo;t work the way you intend it to, look at the source and if you think it&amp;rsquo;s wrong then change it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lesson-3-configuration-is-important-flexible-configuration-is-a-god-send:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Lesson 3: Configuration is important.  Flexible configuration is a god-send.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite parts about hugo is the configurable folder structure.  Currently I&amp;rsquo;m publishing to the project root directory (bad), but in the config file I can specify all of the directories I want to use and where I want hugo to publish those files.  I ran into this issue with Octopress awhile ago and found the &amp;ldquo;use this file structure&amp;rdquo; heavyhandedness really inflexible so this feature was a nice surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lesson-4-there-are-hackfixes-in-every-project:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Lesson 4: There are hackfixes in &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; project.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first tried to deploy the site to github, all of my static file references were 404ing even though they were in the right directories.  I realized after a tiny bit of digging that when you run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it replaces the baseurl param with &amp;ldquo;localhost:1313&amp;rdquo; and puts this all over your site so that static file references work locally.  This is extremely heavyhanded (what if I don&amp;rsquo;t have localhost in /etc/hosts and I don&amp;rsquo;t have permissions to change that file?  Hypothetical.) for a few reasons.  I guess you could get around this by not using absolute paths to reference your static content, but that seems rather &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2005079/absolute-vs-relative-urls&#34;&gt;opinionated&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusions:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran into a few other issues (static files not being copied over into my publish dir frrom my theme folder, customizing the theme, etc.) but all in all I found hugo easy to work with if a bit under-documented.  Most of its power comes from its tiny footprint, speed, and flexible configuration.  I don&amp;rsquo;t mind the hard dependency on Go, but I can see that being a drawback for some (although I find Go configuration and package management much easier to manage than, say, python but I could be biased because I am using a mac with a default python installed and having to remember where python vs python2.7 vs python3 look for their packages is frustrating at best).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one person&amp;rsquo;s experience with one tool, so please take any opinions here with a grain of salt.  However, the lessons learned here apply to any project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>