<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Jill Munson</title>
    <link>http://jillmunson.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Jill Munson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 10:54:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jillmunson.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Homecoming</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2019/12-30/homecoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2019/12-30/homecoming/</guid>
      <description>We need a reboot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Model and The View</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/8-3/model-and-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 17:11:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/8-3/model-and-view/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Are you sure you did that work? I remember things differently.&amp;rdquo;
I&#39;ve never been more sure of anything in my life.
Over the course of a lifetime, I have developed an incredibly well-defined sense of self. In a world of imposter syndrome seminars and #askformore campaigns, it can feel like this identity that I have declared my own is in some way rooted in false bravado. I prefer to think of it as the result of having lived a life running in the debugger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Day at Viacom</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/10-29/goodbye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 17:11:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/10-29/goodbye/</guid>
      <description>At the time of writing, this moment is:
  my last day with Nick digital,
  3 days before I start a cross-country adventure with my micro-family on our way to put down new roots and start the Seattle chapter of our lives,
  2 hours before my going away party starts,
  about 20 minutes before the Minibar delivery gets here.
   I started to wind down the day by writing one of those horrible &amp;ldquo;last day for ______&amp;rdquo; emails that read less like a parting note and more like a final treatise on so-and-so&#39;s insights that will motivate and steer the company towards greatness while complimenting a large number of people that person has probably never met.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craft as meditation</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/8-3/craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 17:11:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/8-3/craft/</guid>
      <description>I get restless sometimes.
I work in the city, and thus have the distinct pleasure of a long train commute. I have lots of time on my hands to do a lot of thinking while sitting still.
I think about lots of things &amp;ndash; work, side projects, what am I doing with my life, etc. but if I&#39;m not doing something with my hands I get perpetually distracted from my own thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello world</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/7-10/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 12:57:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/post/2015/7-10/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m not sure when this all began, but right now it is July 10th and about halfway through what I consider real summer and I have been plagued by this near-constant sense that I should be doing something. It&#39;s not like I don&#39;t keep myself busy, but lately I feel like none of those things require any kind of boundary pushing.
The issue is that even though I like what I&#39;m doing, I don&#39;t feel like I&#39;ve done anything start-to-finish and like I&#39;m learning anything new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jillmunson.com &#43; hugo</title>
      <link>http://jillmunson.com/project/hugo/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 22:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jillmunson.com/project/hugo/about/</guid>
      <description>Github: jaemu.github.io
 One of the biggest weaknesses I have is putting pen to paper, finger to keyboard, etc. without getting overwhelmed by trying to organize something that isn&#39;t even there. Even in writing, my comfort zone was always editing and not content creation (I blame this background for my preference for hunting bugs and re-organizing code than architecting an application from scratch). I think as you get more knowledge without constantly exercising that knowledge with repeated exercise this becomes incredibly common.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>